# ARNAUD DÉCOLASSE

SENIOR ENGINEERING MANAGER

Following a Master's degree in computer science, I now have 15 years of experience as a software engineer.I worked in companies of various sizes and domains, in France and in the United States. After being a full-stack developer for about 10 years, working mostly on back-end side, I progressively grew into leadership roles, first on technical side, then as people manager. I eventually reached a Senior Engineering Manager level at Expedia Group. I oversaw teams up to ten people, mostly developers but also project and product managers, organized in agile teams relying on devOps workflows and tools.



#### **DETAILS**

**PHONE** 

(+33) 06 98 75 59 91

**EMAIL** 

arnaud.decolasse@gmail.com

**ONLINE RESUME** 

adecolasse.com/en

**ADDRESS** 

Paris, France

#### **SKILLS**

PEOPLE MANAGEMENT

AGILE/DEVOPS

PROJECT MANAGEMENT

PRODUCT MANAGEMENT

COACHING

JAVA/KOTLIN

**GRAPHQL** 

**CLOUD AWS** 

**REST API** 

REACT/NODE

### **EXPERIENCE**

Senior Engineering Manager

2021-2023

Traveldoo, Expedia Group | Paris

During my last couple years at Traveldoo, I was promoted to Senior Engineering Manager in charge of the administration and implementation applications. I supervised around ten direct reports of various skills, in a business termination context that made motivation a challenging topic. I organized the work streams so we could keep on providing great product quality and support to our customers, while offering career opportunities to my team members.

**Engineering Manager** 

2018 - 2021

Traveldoo, Expedia Group | Paris

Leader of the 5 people team developing the Expense product at Traveldoo. As manager, I organized the work processes using Agile and Kanban, and coached my direct reports in their career progression. I handled the COVID situation with the challenging situations of full-remote and financial restrictions (hiring freeze, contractors termination). I also managed several freelance developers inside the team.

**Full-Stack Developer** 

2015 - 2018

Traveldoo, Expedia Group | Paris

Senior Software Engineer in the agile development team for the Expense product. I worked on all layers of the application: back-end, front-end, batch. I progressively took a technical leadership role contributing on the new microservices architecture and the Ci/Cd migration.

**Integration Developer** 

2013 - 2015

Sefas USA, Groupe Docapost | Boston

Software engineer on ADF (Automated Document Factory) technologies. Product customization for the customers' needs. Creation of workflows to handle documents creation, merging, processing, printing and mailing. Python and Java languages.

**Full-Stack Developer** 

2011 - 2013

Bouygues Telecom | Paris

Software Engineer on a middle-office application (Gallium) managing millions of mobile phone's clients and contracts. Conception and development leader on new versions, quality and assurance tests, support and bug fixes on the production version.

Java and Flex technologies.

## **EDUCATION**

MASTER'S DEGREE, Computer Science

2006 - 2008

Université Paris Cité

Grade: "Mention Bien", Option: Information Systems

BACHELOR'S DEGREE, Computer Science

2005 - 2006

Université Paris Sorbonne

